Steven Macias

Software Engineer

(786) 246.9655 · stevenmcs22@gmail.com · New York, NY · in/stevenmacias222/ · github.com/stvnmcs

I am a creative-minded, solutions-driven software developer with a passion for intuitive design and function. My previous experiences as a full-time admission counselor and freelance creative endeavors informs everything that I do: from my ability to adapt and adjust plans quickly to finding efficient, concise solutions for challenging problems.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL | Database - PostgreSQL, MongoDB Libraries and Frameworks - React (class based and hooks), Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap Other - RESTful Routing, JSON api

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

May 2024 - Present

Tactico 90 | HTML, Javascript, CSS, MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js

- Prompt: My goal was to create a tool to organize all the soccer events in New York to have it be more easily navigable for individuals who are part of the greater New York soccer community.
- Utilized a HTML, CSS, Java stack (MongoDB, Express, Node.js) to build a full stack application in 2 days. With full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations hitting all RESTful API calls.
- Created application with a mobile-first approach and styled the application using Styled-Components and CSS3 with flexbox layouts.

Coin Toss | HTML, Javascript, CSS, MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js

- Utilized React.js components for the front-end of the application creating an application that organizes client feedback with the use of a voting system.
- Made RESTful API fetch calls to an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and tested all backend routes during development using Postman.
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections.
- Implemented ES6 tagged template literals with Styled-Components along CSS3 to provide style and flexbox layout of the application.

Horizon | HTML, CSS, Django, Bootstrap, Python

- Created a travel application making fetch calls to a Google Maps API.
- Used Python as the primary front-end language to test out its multifaceted capabilities
- Served the back-end of the application using Python methods and functions utilizing MySQL database management.
- Styled and created the visual aspects using Bootstrap, HTML, and CSS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Admissions Counselor, 2U, Inc. | New York, NY

February 2022 - February 2024

- Drove departmental success by building key strategic relationships with stakeholders to develop international interrelationship for domestic students.
- Guided students to the appropriate academic programs, utilizing in-depth profile assessments, and facilitated seamless program enrollment, ensuring a smooth transition for each candidate.
- Contributed to record-breaking success by playing a key role in the company's most successful quarter (Quarter 3), surpassing 3,000 enrolled students in a data-driven vertical.
- Fostered strong relationships with prospective students, providing ongoing support and ensuring they were fully informed and prepared to begin or complete their programs.

Courier, FedEx | Miami, FL

April 2020 - January 2022

- Created a luxury client experience by providing a client-focused relationship which included gifting, shipping, and delivery
- Generated sales and achieved sales goals on a monthly basis while promoting brand values.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE

Software Engineering Immersive

May 2024 - August 2024

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 12-week, 500+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

Florida State University | Tallahassee, FL

Bachelors of Science in Political Science, History

December 2018